<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><title><![CDATA[USC AUV at RoboSub 2013]]></title><date><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2013 03:29:00 -0700]]></date><tags><![CDATA[]]></tags><private><![CDATA[]]></private><content><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;USC AUV attended the International RoboSub Competition for the 12th time this past summer. RoboSub has been held at the Transducer Evaluation Center (TRANSDEC) in San Diego, CA each July since 1997. This year the competition theme was &quot;License to Dive&quot; in honor of RoboSub&#039;s 16th birthday. As always, it was a hectic week, but we finished the competition having accomplished more than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday, July 22nd: Team Orientation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; width:440px;&quot;&gt;Our first day at RoboSub got off to a terrible start - we discovered our brand-new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adl-usa.com/company/&quot;&gt;ADL Embedded Solutions&lt;/a&gt; computer (ADLQM67PC-2715QE) had been damaged during the drive down to San Diego. Fortunately, ADL Embedded Solutions is headquarted in San Diego, less than 20 minutes from our hotel. Our team captain and software lead, Dylan Foster, spent the day testing the damaged computer with ADL&#039;s very helpful engineers. Meanwhile, the rest of our small team attended the RoboSub Team Orientation. The night was spent working on software and fixing some damaged electrical connections.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://robotics.usc.edu/~uscauv/blog/data/uploads/images/adl.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px; height: 132px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; clear:both;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; clear:both;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, July 23rd &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, July 24th: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-water Practice Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dylan returned to ADL to work out some solution for the damaged computer. The rest of the team arrived looking pretty haggard on Tuesday morning to TRANSDEC and moved into our booth and home base for the week. We waited with baited breath for news about the computer. Lucky for us, the guys at ADL take customer service to an entirely new level. Dylan managed to secure a loaner computer for the week to replace our irreparably damaged one. We were back in the game! Unfortunately, without a computer we were not able to test in-water at all on Tuesday, which was a major cause for concern as we approached qualifying runs. We celebrated ADL&#039;s generosity with burritos, then returned to the hotel to install and test the new computer. Wednesday was spent testing software with the new computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, July 25th: Qualifying Run&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday morning brought yet another setback - Seabee&#039;s hard drive had failed and was unusable. Thankfully team member Janet Kim had brought two laptops, and was kind enough to lend Seabee a hard drive for the remainder of competition. After hooking up the hard drive, we spent the day at TRANSDEC tuning Seabee&#039;s ability to dive 1 meter and drive straight reliably. Our last chance to qualify for competition was approaching rapidly, and at 5pm Seabee entered the waters of TRANSDEC for the first time at RoboSub 2013. We qualified easily, driving straight through the gate on the first try.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://robotics.usc.edu/~uscauv/blog/data/uploads/images/2013-07-26%2010.50.58_cropped.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px; height: 507px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, July 26th: Static Judging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent most of Friday in the dolphin pool, refining Seabee&#039;s ability to locate and drive towards a buoy. Our mechanical lead, Brennan Swanton, stoicly braved the cold water for hours on end. We took a break to present for static judging, and placed 7th on the strength of our journal paper, video, website, and vehicle design. We planned to continuing testing in the pool throughout the night back at the hotel. However, upon arrival at the pool we discovered that Seabee was no longer holding pressure. The O-rings that seal the hull had been damaged at some point and needed to be replaced.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://robotics.usc.edu/~uscauv/blog/data/uploads/images/2013-07-27%2012.36.13_smaller.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px; height: 486px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, July 27th: Semifinals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most of the team headed to TRANSDEC, a few team members drove off in search of O-rings. Our usual suppliers were either out or didn&#039;t carry the unusual size of O-rings we needed. We were able to purchase them at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sandiegoseal.com/&quot;&gt;San Diego Seal, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and get Seabee back in the water for testing. This time electrical lead Turner Topping went for a swim while Dylan continued to tune his code. Our afternoon semifinal run went relatively well - Seabee drove straight through the gate, aligned with a path segment, and autonomously bumped two buoys. In previous years the team has never acheived this level of autonomous operation. At the end of the day we were ranked 9th, placing us in competition for the last wild card slot in the finals. The night was spent in the hotel pool testing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://robotics.usc.edu/~uscauv/blog/data/uploads/images/2013-07-28%2005.46.54_smaller.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px; height: 486px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, July 28th: Finals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were given a final run to qualify for the wild card slot in the finals at noon on Sunday. We needed to score a minimum of 1500 points to qualify, a tall order. Sadly, we came short of this goal. Seabee got tangled in the buoy&#039;s tether after bumping it, and we spent most of our 20 minute run waiting for her to be rescued. Out of the competition, we stuck around to watch some of the finals and socialize with other teams. We had a great time trading stories and joking about the eternal frustrations and rewards of working on an AUV. See you all next year at TRANSDEC!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://robotics.usc.edu/~uscauv/blog/data/uploads/images/robosub_2013_team_photo.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px; height: 485px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content></item>
